Normalization is the process of ensuring that
an entity in a database has a solid design
and that the data in the entity can
work well with other entities as needed.
There are several forms of normalization,
but the first form of normalization
ensures that every record is unique and
that fields are independent of each other.
Take a look at this data example. Is there
any field that ensures each record in this
entity is unique? At first glance, no. Thus,
we should add a primary key field to this data.
I will add a field to the left of the existing
fields and number these records accordingly.
The second problem is that sorting on the name
field can be problematic because we have the
first and last names in the same field.
In first normal form (1NF), each field
needs to have a single value so that data
can be sorted in any way possible. Normally,
I would use a formula to separate these, but given
we have so few names here, I will just quickly
add a column and separate these names manually.
To recap, in the first step for normalization, we
want to make sure that every record in an entity
is unique and every field has a single value.